Planned Parenthood League of Massachusetts, 1859-2002 (bulk 1916-1960)
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES VII. RESOURCE FILES
  - Adoption, [see Countries - U.S.-Tennessee]
    - Countries
      - Canada 1935, 1964, undated (Box 96, Folder 3)
      - China 1933-65, undated, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES] (Box 96, Folder 4)
      - Cuba 1938, 1941 (Box 96, Folder 5)
      - Europe
        - France and Germany 1940-41 (Box 96, Folder 6)
        - Netherlands 1937-38, undated (Box 96, Folder 7)
        - Sweden 1937, undated (Box 96, Folder 8)
      - Great Britain
        - England, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES]
          - Articles 1942-6, undated (Box 96, Folder 9)
          - Family Planning Association 1959-61 (Box 96, Folder 10)
          - Pamphlets
            - Marie Stopes 1925, 1933 (Box 96, Folder 11)
            - Miscellaneous 1925-54, undated (Box 96, Folder 12)
          - Pioneer Health Centre, Peckham 1936-49, undated (Box 96, Folder 13)
        - Ireland 1939-49 (Box 97, Folder 1)
        - Scotland 1932-35, undated (Box 97, Folder 2)
      - India, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES]
        - Family Planning Association of India Bulletin 1959-63 (Box 97, Folder 3)
        - Miscellaneous 1936-62 (Box 97, Folder 4)
      - Iranundated (Box 97, Folder 5)
      - Jamaicaundated (Box 97, Folder 6)
      - Japan, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES]
        - Japan Planned Parenthood Quarterly 1950-52 (Box 97, Folder 7)
        - Miscellaneous 1950-66, undated (Box 97, Folder 8)
      - Korea, Singapore, and Taiwan 1945-67 (Box 97, Folder 9)
      - Latin America 1946-66, undated, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES] (Box 97, Folder 10)
      - New Zealandundated (Box 97, Folder 11)
      - Pakistan 1959-65, undated (Box 97, Folder 12)
      - USSR 1933-66, undated (Box 97, Folder 13)
      - United States
        - Alabama 1941, undated (Box 98, Folder 1)
        - Arkansasundated (Box 98, Folder 2)
        - Arizona 1942-47 (Box 98, Folder 3)
        - California 1930-65, undated (Box 98, Folder 4)
        - Colorado 1961-65 (Box 98, Folder 5)
        - Connecticut 1932-64, undated, [see also SERIES IV RELATED ORGANIZATIONS - Planned Parenthood of Connecticut, SERIES VI. LEGISTLATIVE FILES - Connecticut, and SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES] (Box 98, Folder 6)
        - Delaware 1947-49 (Box 98, Folder 7)
        - District of Columbia
          - Birth Control Policies and Procedures Manual 1964? (Box 98, Folder 8)
          - Printed material 1947-64, undated (Box 98, Folder 9)
        - Florida 1933-59, n.d (Box 98, Folder 10)
        - Georgia 1966, undated (Box 98, Folder 11)
        - Illinois
          - Newsletters 1948-65 (Box 98, Folder 12)
          - Publications, memos, and history 1934-65, undated (Box 98, Folder 13)
        - Indiana-Kentucky 1937-65, undated (Box 98, Folder 14)
        - Maine 1935 (Box 98, Folder 15)
        - Maryland 1965 (Box 98, Folder 16)
        - Michigan 1933-60 (Box 98, Folder 17)
        - Minnesota1931-65, undated (Box 98, Folder 18)
        - Missouri - Nebraska 1953-68, undated (Box 98, Folder 19)
        - New Hampshire 1934-35, undated (Box 98, Folder 20)
        - New Jersey 1932-62 (Box 98, Folder 21)
        - New Mexico 1969 (Box 99, Folder 1)
        - New York 1934-66, undated (Box 99, Folder 2)
        - North Carolina 1940 (Box 99, Folder 3)
        - North Dakota 1948, undated (Box 99, Folder 4)
        - Ohio 1931-67, undated (Box 99, Folder 5)
        - Oklahoma 1950-53 (Box 99, Folder 6)
        - Pennsylvania 1928-66, undated (Box 99, Folder 7)
        - Puerto Rico 1938-64, undated (Box 99, Folder 8)
        - Rhode Island
          - Rhode Island Birth Control League 1933-36, undated (Box 99, Folder 9)
          - Rhode Island Maternal Health Association
            - Board of Directors 1959-61 (Box 99, Folder 10)
            - Printed material and reports 1957-61 (Box 99, Folder 11)
          - Miscellaneous printed material 1930-31, undated (Box 99, Folder 12)
        - Tennessee 1941, 1964 (Box 100, Folder 1)
        - Texas 1947-54 (Box 100, Folder 2)
        - Vermont 1932-35, undated (Box 100, Folder 3)
        - Virginia 1941-54 (Box 100, Folder 4)
        - Washington 1961 (Box 100, Folder 5)
        - West Virginia - Wisconsin 1934-66, undated (Box 100, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous 1927-55, undated, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES - International] (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - Crime
      - Juvenile delinquency 1930-39, undated (Box 100, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous 1934-60 (Box 100, Folder 9)
    - Economic issues
      - Employment 1930-63, undated (Box 100, Folder 10)
      - Poverty 1964-67 (Box 100, Folder 11)
      - U.S. aid to developing countries 1959-61, [see also Population Policy] (Box 100, Folder 12)
      - Welfare 1929-68, undated (Box 100, Folder 13)
      - Miscellaneous 1929-66, undated (Box 100, Folder 14)
    - Eugenics, [see also Organizations-American Eugenics Society and SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES]
      - Journal of Heredity 1937-46, undated (Box 100, Folder 15)
      - Miscellaneous 1929-56, undated (Box 100, Folder 16)
    - Family, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES]
      - Fatherhood 1938-40, undated (Box 100, Folder 17)
      - Motherhood
        - International Mother Digest 1950 (Box 100, Folder 18)
        - Unwed mothers 1966 (Box 100, Folder 19)
      - Miscellaneous 1936-65 (Box 100, Folder 20)
    - Family planning
      - "Implementing DHEW Policy on Family Planning and Population" 1967 (Box 101, Folder 1)
      - Printed material 1960-68, undated (Box 101, Folder 2)
      - Public policy and strategy 1952-65 (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Fertility and infertility
      - Journal of Human Fertility 1940-46 (Box 101, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous printed material 1926-60, undated (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - Genetics 1953 (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - Health
      - "Health Examinations: A Manual for the General Practitioner" 1947 (Box 101, Folder 7)
      - Maternal health 1931 (Box 101, Folder 8)
      - Mental health 1935-38, undated (Box 101, Folder 9)
      - Public health
        - "Family Planning Services in Public Health Programs" 1966 (Box 101, Folder 10)
        - Massachusetts Department of Public Health 1938-39, undated (Box 101, Folder 11)
        - "Proposal for a task force approach to incorporation of birth control services in public hospitals and public welfare programs," undated (Box 101, Folder 12)
        - Statistics 1921-46, undated (Box 101, Folder 13)
        - Miscellaneous 1926-59, undated (Box 101, Folder 14)
        - Venereal disease 1919-45, undated (Box 102, Folder 1)
      - Housing 1935-39 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Individuals
      - Dickinson, Robert Latou 1950-71 (Box 102, Folder 3)
      - Ernst, Morris 1938 (Box 102, Folder 4)
      - Guttmacher, Alan 1959, [see also Organizations-Alan Guttmacher Institute and Human Betterment Foundation] (Box 102, Folder 5)
      - Kennedy, John F. 1957-59, undated, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES] (Box 102, Folder 6)
      - Pincus, Gregory 1967 (Box 102, Folder 7)
      - Rock, John
        - "Birth Control is Not Enough" 1949-50, undated (Box 102, Folder 8)
        - Clippings 1948-68, undated (Box 102, Folder 9)
        - Miscellaneous 1940-68, undated (Box 102, Folder 10)
      - Sanger, Margaret, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES]
        - Articles and tributes 1935-61, undated (Box 102, Folder 11)
        - Writings and pamphlets 1920-40, undated (Box 102, Folder 12)
        - Douglas McArthur 1949-50 (Box 102, Folder 13)
      - Stone, Hannah and Abraham 1929-54 (Box 103, Folder 1)
      - Sugrue, Thomas 1953, undated (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - Marriage
      - Counseling 1933-57, undated (Box 103, Folder 3)
      - Guides 1929-57, undated (Box 103, Folder 4)
      - War marriage 1944 (Box 103, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous 1935-63 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Media 1941-66, undated (Box 103, Folder 7)
    - Menstruation 1941, undated (Box 103, Folder 8)
    - Minorities 1964-68, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES - Blacks and birth control] (Box 103, Folder 9)
    - Mortality (Box 103)
      - Infant 1929-41, undated (Box 104, Folder 1)
      - Maternal 1928-44, undated (Box 104, Folder 2)
      - Statistics 1938-40 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - Organizations (Box 104)
      - Academy of Foreign Relationsundated (Box 104, Folder 4)
      - Alan Guttmacher Instituteundated (Box 104, Folder 5)
      - American Association of Social Workers 1936-39, undated (Box 104, Folder 6)
      - American Association of University Women (Boston Branch) 1941 (Box 104, Folder 7)
      - American Civil Liberties Union 1938, 1970, undated (Box 104, Folder 8)
      - American Eugenics Society 1934-56, undated (Box 104, Folder 9)
      - American Institute of Public Opinionundated (Box 104, Folder 10)
      - American Medical Association 1936-39 (Box 104, Folder 11)
      - American Social Hygiene Association 1936-42, undated (Box 104, Folder 12)
      - American Unitarian Association 1938-40 (Box 105, Folder 1)
      - Beth Israel Hospital 1935 (Box 105, Folder 2)
      - Boston Council of Social Agencies 1939-43 (Box 105, Folder 3)
      - Boston Health League 1941-43 (Box 105, Folder 4)
      - Boston Hospital for Women 1967, undated (Box 105, Folder 5)
      - Boston Legal Aid Society 1935 (Box 105, Folder 6)
      - Boston Redevelopment Agency 1962, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES] (Box 105, Folder 7)
      - Brookline Association for Mental Healthundated (Box 105, Folder 8)
      - Bureau of Marriage Counsel and Sex Educationundated (Box 105, Folder 9)
      - Campaign to Check the Population Explosion 1919-70, undated (Box 105, Folder 10)
      - Center for Regional Economic Studies (University of Pittsburgh) 1964 (Box 105, Folder 11)
      - Central Indexundated (Box 105, Folder 12)
      - Citizens Committee for Planned Parenthood 1938, undated (Box 105, Folder 13)
      - Civil Liberties Committee of Massachusetts 1938-48, undated (Box 105, Folder 14)
      - Committee of Physiciansundated (Box 105, Folder 15)
      - Committee on Maternal Health 1917-28, undated (Box 105, Folder 16)
      - Community Health Association 1935-41, undated (Box 105, Folder 17)
      - Community Relations Program 1969 (Box 105, Folder 18)
      - Family Guidance Service 1936, undated (Box 105, Folder 19)
      - Family Planning Association 1949-59, undated (Box 105, Folder 20)
      - Family Welfare Association of America 1938, undated (Box 105, Folder 21)
      - Family Welfare Society of Boston 1930-36 (Box 105, Folder 22)
      - Federal Communications Commission 1946-49, undated (Box 105, Folder 23)
      - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America Information Service 1941-58, undated (Box 106, Folder 1)
      - Florence Crittenton League of Compassion, Inc.undated (Box 106, Folder 2)
      - Greater Boston Federation of Churches 1933 (Box 106, Folder 3)
      - House of the Good Samaritan 1939 (Box 106, Folder 4)
      - Human Betterment Foundation 1936-39, undated (Box 106, Folder 5)
      - Institute of Family Relations 1933-39, undated (Box 106, Folder 6)
      - International Committee on Planned Parenthood 1950 (Box 106, Folder 7)
      - Junior League 1937-38, undated (Box 106, Folder 8)
      - League of Women Voters 1936-39, undated (Box 106, Folder 9)
      - Lowell Institute 1949 (Box 106, Folder 10)
      - Marriage Study Associationundated (Box 106, Folder 11)
      - Massachusetts Central Health Council 1938-45, undated (Box 106, Folder 12)
      - Massachusetts Civic League. Special Committee to Oppose Lottery Legislation 1941, undated (Box 106, Folder 13)
      - Massachusetts Conference of Social Work 1952-54 (Box 106, Folder 14)
      - Massachusetts Council of Church Women 1951 (Box 106, Folder 15)
      - Massachusetts Council of Churches 1945-64, undated (Box 106, Folder 16)
      - Massachusetts Federation of Women's Church Societies 1942 (Box 106, Folder 17)
      - Massachusetts Forest and Park Associationundated (Box 106, Folder 18)
      - Massachusetts Society for Social Hygiene 1936-53, undated (Box 106, Folder 19)
      - Massachusetts State Federation of Women's Clubs 1935-48, undated (Box 106, Folder 20)
      - Massachusetts Tuberculosis and Health League 1952-58 (Box 106, Folder 21)
      - Milbank Memorial Fundundated (Box 106, Folder 22)
      - National Association of Broadcasters 1939 (Box 106, Folder 23)
      - National Child Labor Committeeundated (Box 106, Folder 24)
      - National Civic Federation, Women's Department 1935 (Box 106, Folder 25)
      - National Committee for Medical Rights in Massachusetts 1942, undated (Box 106, Folder 26)
      - National Committee on Maternal Health 1930-61, undated (Box 106, Folder 27)
      - National Conference on Family Relationsundated (Box 106, Folder 28)
      - National Conference of Social Work 1937-42 (Box 107, Folder 1)
      - National Council of Parent Education 1941 (Box 107, Folder 2)
      - National Economy League 1937 (Box 107, Folder 3)
      - National Education Association 1947-48, undated (Box 107, Folder 4)
      - National Medical Council on Birth Control 1937-41, undated (Box 107, Folder 5)
      - Pathfinder Club 1968, undated (Box 107, Folder 6)
      - National Urban League 1966, undated (Box 107, Folder 7)
      - Parent Instituteundated (Box 107, Folder 8)
      - Population Reference Bureau
        - Population Bulletin 1946-66 (Box 107, Folder 9)
        - Population Profile, 1961-67 (Box 107, Folder 10)
        - Miscellaneous publications and newsletters 1940-69, undated (Box 107, Folder 11)
      - UNESCO 1950 (Box 107, Folder 12)
      - Unitarian Fellowship for Social Justice 1942 (Box 107, Folder 13)
      - United Nations 1957-63 (Box 107, Folder 14)
      - Wellesley Conferences 1937-39 (Box 107, Folder 15)
      - World Health Organization 1965, undated (Box 107, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous organizations 1935-65, undated (Box 107, Folder 17)
    - Politics 1942-61, undated (Box 107, Folder 18)
    - Population, [see also Organizations - Population Reference Bureau and SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES]
      - Census (Massachusetts) 1935-38 (Box 108, Folder 1)
      - Conferences
        - Dallas 1960 (Box 108, Folder 2)
        - New England Assembly on the Populations Dilemma 1964 (Box 108, Folder 3)
        - New Hampshire Conference on Population Problems 1965 (Box 108, Folder 4)
      - Food supply 1941-63, undated (Box 108, Folder 5)
      - Policy and theory: articles, clippings, reports, and printed material
        - 1930-49 (Box 108, Folder 6-12)
        - 1950-69, undated (Box 109, Folder 1-7)
      - Miscellaneous 1952-65, undated (Box 109, Folder 8)
    - Pregnancy 1931-52 (Box 109, Folder 9)
    - Religion
      - Catholic church, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES]
        - "The Authority of the Roman Catholic Church" 1940 (Box 109, Folder 10)
        - Articles, notes, and printed material 1931-65, undated (Box 109, Folder 11)
        - Birth control
          - "The Apostolate of the Midwife," discourse by Pope Pius XII 1951 (Box 110, Folder 1)
          - Articles 1940-49, undated (Box 110, Folder 2-3)
          - Notes 1930-52 (Box 110, Folder 4-6)
        - Blanshard, Paul 1948-51, undated (Box 110, Folder 7)
        - Church and state separation 1940-52, undated (Box 110, Folder 8)
        - "Handbook of Moral Theology" (readings from)undated (Box 110, Folder 9)
        - Pamphlets 1941-68, undated (Box 110, Folder 10)
        - Politics 1938-59, undated (Box 110, Folder 11)
        - Statistics
          - Massachusetts 1936-53, undated (Box 110, Folder 12)
          - United States 1940-56, undated (Box 110, Folder 13)
      - Non-Catholic
        - Birth control 1917-64 (Box 110, Folder 14)
        - Protestant/Catholic relations 1952-63 (Box 111, Folder 1)
        - Unitarian 1967-68, undated (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Sex Education 1925-71, undated (Box 111, Folder 3-4)
- SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES, [see also SERIES X. MICROFILM]
  - Notebook file of article digests 1916-38 (Box 112)
  - Subject files
    - Abortion 1938, 1957-71, undated (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - American Medical Association resolution on birth control
      - Anti 1937-38 (Box 113, Folder 2)
      - Pro 1937-38 (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - Birthrate 1935-51, undated (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - Blacks and birth control 1962-68 (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - Blanchard, Paul 1945-51, undated (Box 113, Folder 6)
    - Boston Redevelopment Authority 1962-63, undated (Box 113, Folder 7)
    - Catholic church
      - Cardinal Spellman and Eleanor Roosevelt 1942-59 (Box 113, Folder 8)
      - Numbers of Catholics 1938-50, undated (Box 113, Folder 9)
      - Pope Pius XII statement on marriage 1951 (Box 113, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous 1935-68, undated (Box 114, Folder 1-3)
    - China 1935-66 (Box 114, Folder 4)
    - Church and state 1947-52, undated (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Clinic raids and trial
      - Brookline 1937-41, undated (Box 114, Folder 6)
      - Salem 1934-42 (Box 114, Folder 7)
    - Conant, James B. 1951 (Box 114, Folder 8)
    - Connecticut
      - Law and legislation 1952-81, undated (Box 115, Folder 1-3)
      - Test case 1959-65, undated (Box 115, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous 1948-65, undated (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Contraception
      - Advertisements 1933-38, undated (Box 115, Folder 6)
      - Pill 1957-69, undated (Box 115, Folder 7)
      - Rhythm 1965, undated (Box 115, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous 1938-67, undated (Box 115, Folder 9)
      - Opinions 1931-49 (Box 115, Folder 10)
    - Doctors and birth control 1937-67, undated (Box 115, Folder 11)
    - Editorials 1947-65, undated (Box 115, Folder 12)
    - England 1945-55, undated (Box 115, Folder 13)
    - Eugenics 1932-49, undated (Box 115, Folder 14)
    - Families 1948-65, undated (Box 115, Folder 15)
    - India 1950-67, undated (Box 115, Folder 16)
    - International 1937-68, undated (Box 115, Folder 17)
    - Japan 1938-62 (Box 115, Folder 18)
    - Kennedy, John F. 1959-61, undated (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Latin America 1950-68, undated (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - Massachusetts
      - Meetings 1945-53, undated (Box 116, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous 1930-69, undated (Box 116, Folder 4-8)
    - Natural law 1942-65 (Box 116, Folder 9)
    - New York
      - Hospital disputes
        - New York City 1958-59 (Box 116, Folder 10)
        - Poughkeepsie 1952, undated (Box 116, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous 1965, undated (Box 116, Folder 12)
    - O'Neil, James 1951-53, undated (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Point Four 1950-52, undated (Box 117, Folder 2)
    - Population
      - Catholic views 1950-65 (Box 117, Folder 3)
      - Food supply 1948-66, undated (Box 117, Folder 4)
      - International 1949-77, undated (Box 117, Folder 5-6)
      - United States 1938-68, undated (Box 117, Folder 7)
    - Poverty 1964-68, undated (Box 117, Folder 8)
    - Puerto Rico 1948-60 (Box 117, Folder 9)
    - Radio 1948-65, undated (Box 117, Folder 10)
    - Religious groups 1935-61, undated (Box 117, Folder 11)
    - Sanger, Margaret 1935-66, undated, [See also SERIES VII. RESOURCE FILES and SERIES III. CENTRAL ADMINISTRATIVE FILES - Publicity - Sanger tour of Massachusetts] (Box 117, Folder 12)
    - United Nations and World Health Organization 1946-67, undated, [see also Population] (Box 117, Folder 13)
    - United States
      - Foreign aid 1948-67 (Box 117, Folder 14)
      - Policies on birth control 1952-67, undated (Box 117, Folder 15)
    - Welfare 1935-68, undated (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Welfare Council dispute (New York City) 1953, undated (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - Women's clubs and birth control 1935-51, undated (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - Chronological files
    - 1934 - Jul 1965 (Box 118, Folder 4-11)
    - Aug 1965-1969, undated (Box 119, Folder 1-9)
- SERIES IX. OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Sound recordings
    - Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau: "Why Let Them Die", Part 2 and 3 1938 [16" records] (Box 120, Folder 1-2)
    - Planned Parenthood League of Massachusetts
      - Broadcasts
        - 4 different 1 minute spots 1951 [12" record] (Box 120, Folder 3)
        - 4 different 1 minute spots 1951, Ruth Putnam Show [12" record] (Box 120, Folder 4)
        - Birth Control, 1, 2, 3undated [16" records] (Box 120, Folder 5-9)
        - Birth Control Part 2undated [16" record] (Box 120, Folder 10)
        - Birth Control, Pro and Con 1951 [12" record] (Box 120, Folder 11-12)
        - Committee Opposing adoption of referendum #4
          - 5 minute program, Italian program [16" record] (Box 120, Folder 13)
          - 15 minute program #1 and 21948 [16" record] (Box 120, Folder 14)
          - 15 minute program #3 and 41948 [16" record] (Box 120, Folder 15)
          - 5 minute program 4, 5 minute program #5, 5 minute program #41948 [16" record] (Box 120, Folder 16)
          - 15 minute program 61948 [16" record] (Box 120, Folder 17)
          - Dr. Emery Stevens Bucke 1949 [16" record] (Box 120, Folder 18)
          - Dr. Walter Meier 1948 [16" record] (Box 120, Folder 19)
        - Mother's Health Committee
          - Dr. Ira Dixon [12" records] (Box 121, Folder 1-3)
          - 4, 5, 6 [16" records] (Box 121, Folder 4-8)
          - 10 minute program [16" records] (Box 121, Folder 9-12)
        - Planned Parenthood Referendum Committee
          - #1 [16" record] (Box 121, Folder 13)
          - #3 [16" records] (Box 121, Folder 14-15)
          - 4, 5, 7 [16" records] (Box 121, Folder 16-17)
          - #6 [16" records] (Box 121, Folder 18-19)
          - # 6, 7 [16" record] (Box 121, Folder 20)
          - #7 [16" record] (Box 121, Folder 21)
      - Unidentified [16" record] (Box 121, Folder 22)
    - "Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Purpose: Survival. A Planned Parenthood Documentary," narrated by Basil Rathboneundated [12" record] (Box 121, Folder 23)
  - Oversize material removed from main body of records
    - Flat File (Map-case 122)
      - New York ClipperFebruary 26, 1859 (Map-case 122)
      - Initiative and Referendum posterundated (Map-case 122)
      - List of organizations endorsing amendments exempting the medical profession from existing statues relating to the prevention of conceptionundated (2 copies) (Map-case 122)
      - Poster: "Birth Control to Save a Mother's Life… Vote Yes on Question 4," undated (Map-case 122)
- SERIES X. MICROFILM
  - Birth control League of Massachusetts
    - May 1930-Sep 1931
      - Massachusetts House of Representatives Bill No. 43: "The Doctor's Bill" to legalize dissemination of birth control information by doctors in Massachusetts (Reel 1)
      - Senator Gillett, Republican of Massachusetts introduced bill to authorize birth control information by physicians, hospitals, clinics and medical schools (Reel 1)
      - Churches and support for birth control (Reel 1)
    - Mar 1931-Mar 1935 (Reel 1)
      - Controversy in publicity: Blanche Ames Ames and Cornelia Cannon in advertisementJan 1935 (Reel 1)
      - Blanche Ames Ames and the Catholic Church: concerning the parent's petition (Reel 1)
      - Margaret Sanger talks in BostonMar 1935 (Reel 1)
    - Oct 1935- Apr 1936 (Reel 1)
      - Connecticut birth control clinics (Reel 1)
      - Massachusetts clinics (Reel 1)
      - Salem walkout at mill over restrictions on married women (Reel 1)
      - Catholic opposition to birth control (Reel 1)
    - Mar 1935-Oct 1935
      - Relief and birth control (Reel 2)
      - Mrs. Sanger speaks in Rhode island (Reel 2)
      - Talks on birth control (Reel 2)
      - McHugh Bill proposed in Massachusetts House: anti-birth control (Reel 2)
      - Groups for and against (Reel 2)
    - Apr 1936-Jun 1939 (Reel 2)
      - General (Reel 2)